houghton.edu 2019-03-05

# Privacy Policy for Houghton College

Privacy Policy for Houghton College
At Houghton College, accessible from www.houghton.edu, one of our main priorities is the privacy of
our visitors. This Privacy Policy document contains types of information that is collected and
recorded by Houghton College and how we use it.
If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate
to contact us through email at webcoordinator@houghton.edu
Log Files
Houghton College follows a standard procedure of using log files. These files log visitors when they
visit websites. All hosting companies do this and it is a part of hosting services' analytics. The
information collected by log files include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet
Service Provider (ISP), date and time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks.
These are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. The purpose of the information
is for analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movement on the website, and
gathering demographic information.
Cookies and Web Beacons
Like any other website, Houghton College uses 'cookies'. These cookies are used to store
information including visitors' preferences, and the pages on the website that the visitor accessed or
visited. The information is used to optimize the users' experience by customizing our web page
content based on visitors' browser type and/or other information.
Third-party ad servers or ad networks uses technologies like cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons
that are used in their respective advertisements and links that appear on Houghton College, which
are sent directly to users' browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs.
These technologies are used to measure the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns and/or to
personalize the advertising content that you see on websites that you visit.
Note that Houghton College has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-
party advertisers.
You can choose to disable cookies through your individual browser options. To find more detailed
information about cookie management with specific web browsers, please refer to the specific
browser website.
Children’s Information
Houghton College does not knowingly collect any Personal Identifiable Information from children
under the age of 13. If you think that your child provided this kind of information on our website, we
strongly encourage you to contact us immediately and we will do our best efforts to promptly remove
such information from our records.
Security

We take reasonable and appropriate steps to protect from unauthorized access or disclosure any
personal information that you share with us.
Contact Us
If you would like to learn more about our privacy policy, or to access your personally identifiable
information contained on our website, you may contact us at:
Houghton College – Office of Marketing and Communications
publicrelations@houghton.edu
585-567-9200
Links to Other Sites
Some Houghton College webpages may include links to sites external to the College, and/or links to
websites that are maintained by individual faculty, staff or students. Houghton College is not
responsible for the content and the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be
aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that
collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information
collected by this website.
Notification of Changes
Houghton College reserves the right, at its discretion, to make changes to this policy at any time.
Please check this privacy policy webpage periodically for amendments/updates.
Online Privacy Policy Only
This privacy policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website with
regards to the information that they shared and/or collect in Houghton College. This policy is not
applicable to any information collected offline or via channels other than this website.
Consent
By using our website, you hereby consent to our Privacy Policy and agree to its Terms and
Conditions.
